# **AAYUSH VERMA**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Ph.- 7031656300 # Email- vermaaayush1309@gmail.com # LinkedIn- linkedin.com/in/aayush-verma-238413175/

# **Objective**

Focused individual with a good academic record and a hefty knowledge in the field of Computer Science, having an experience of 2 years in the Software Engineering and Software Development process.

A motivated and enthusiastic learner and always ready to solve problems in a challenging position with a positive mindset and contribute to the growth of organization by putting the knowledge acquired over the time.

# **Technical Skill Highlights**

- C
- C++
- Core Java
- Python
- Testing (Unit, Black box, White box)
- OOPS

- HTML
- CSS
- Agile/Scrum Methodology
- Embedded C
- Java Card
- MySQL

#### **Tools used**

- JIRA
- GIT/GITHUB
- Eclipse
- Visual Studio Code

# **Professional Experience**

#### Software Engineer - 07/2020 to Present

#### IDEMIA, Noida

- Working as a Software Engineer in the SET R&D (Secure Enterprise & Transaction) team.
- Followed Agile Software Development process for the completion of projects on time.
- Implemented assigned tasks with high quality.
- Understood and adhere to coding guidelines of the team.
- Took ownership of the features/modules within the project.
- Involved in designing and writing test cases for the developed feature.
- Participated in bug fixing of the code.
- Met challenging deadlines while ensuring code quality.

## Associate Software Engineer - 01/2020 to 06/2020

IDEMIA, Noida

- Studied the ISO documents and understood the standards on which the organization is working.
- Developed a code for parsing the ATR needed for communication between a smart card and the terminal
- Involved in the then ongoing CCC (Car Connectivity Consortium) project and understood the code base.
- Debug the code and fixed bugs.
- Involved in designing SRS (Software Requirement Specification) document for a particular feature /module.

# **Internships**

## Aspirevision Tech Education, Kolkata - 06/2019 to 07/2019

- Underwent a four-week training on Internet of Things.
- Developed and built a Password based Door locking System with Email sending provision as a security against theft, using Arduino.

#### Internshala (online)- 06/2018 to 08/2018

- Underwent a 6 week training on HTML, CSS, Bootstrap.
- Developed a responsive cover page for an online Maths Tutorial website.

## **Education**

# Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science & Engineering) - 2016-2020 Sikkim Manipal Institute of Technology, Sikkim-Majhitar.

- Scored an overall 8.94 CGPA in the B.Tech course.
- Represented CSE department as the Deputy General Secretory and was involved in various cultural fest.
- Involved in the management of the second International Conference on Advanced Computational & Communication Paradigms-2019, Sikkim.

#### Senior Secondary Examination: - 2014-2016

D.B.M.S English School, Jamshedpur.

- Scored 89.4 % in Indian School Certificate (ISC) examination in Science field.
- Represented the school as Director of the Rotaract Club, Jamshedpur.
- Conducted multiple events in the school.

#### Secondary Examination: - 2002-2014

D.B.M.S English School, Jamshedpur.

• Scored 88.33 % in Indian Certificate of Secondary Examination (ICSE) in Science field.

# **Projects**

## SCOSTA (Smart Card Operating System for Transport Applications) :- 12/2021 to present

The project involves the low level development of Hardware Abstraction Layer that is needed to support the communication between the Smart Card operating system and the CAD (Card

Acceptance Device). Hardware Abstraction Layer (HAL) acts as a BIOS for OS and it is different for different Smart Card chips. HAL migration was done from SCF250I chip to SCB256I chip. Memory architecture was different so address mapping (logical/physical) is done accordingly on the basis of chip datasheet.

The corresponding test cases were executed in order to check the memory alignment. Any bugs/failures were solved parallelly.

#### NTT-DOCOMO :- 10/2020 to 03/2021

This was the second project at IDEMIA for the customer DOCOMO (Japan) in which I played a role of an agile developer. Participated in studying of the documents, implementing the requirements/features through code and then testing of the feature developed. Also participated in code review exercises with the other team members as well as the team lead.

#### CCC (Car Connectivity Consortium) :- 01/2020 to 08/2020

This was the internship project at IDEMIA. I was the member of an agile team that handled the Connected Car project for Hyundai and KIA motors. The main aim was to develop a secure element in the car's engine for mutual authentication with the owner's digital key to preform different functionalities in the car such as door lock/unlock, engine start etc.

I was involved in developing APIs and improving the existing APIs on Java Card technology for the applet loaded on the secure element of car's ECU. I also did the white-box testing of the applet keeping in view of the implemented features and also fixed bugs during the process.

I also developed a demo applet on Java Card to simulate the communication between ECU and CCC controller.

#### GPS-GSM based Tracking System (B.TECH 7th Semester): 08/2019 to 12/2019

This project presented a device model with a GPS and GSM module. The purpose was to develop a tracking device which is useful for all sort of people and will help them to track their lost objects such as bags, vehicles etc.

Microcontroller Arduino Uno was interfaced with GPS SKG13BL and GSM 900A module. The entire programming was done in **Embedded C** on Arduino.

## **Achievements**

 Awarded as the performer of the month (IDEMIA) in October 2021 for resolving issues found during the testing and personalization of the SIM applications which lead to timely delivery of the project.